Shane Pinnell

Information Technology Management

email: shane.pinnell@gmail.com

web: shanepinnell.com twitter: @shane_pinnell phone: (909) 581-2429

Summary of Qualifications

Experienced leader of Information Technology teams that focus on service and support of end users and the organizations mission and goals. Well rounded knowledge of Information Technology stemming from over fifteen years of experience leveraging a diverse skill set including, but not limited to the following:

Networking

Programming

Database Administration

Server Management

Cyber Security

Directory Services

Application support

VoIP administration

Client support

Education

Azusa Pacific University, Azusa CAB.S. Management Information Systems

Perris High School, Perris CA
High School Diploma

Work Experience

Chief Technology Officer 05/2019 - Present: Colton Joint Unified School District, Colton CA

Worked to improve cyber-security posture. Managed the deployment of over 18,000 devices to students and the transition to remote work for over 2,500 staff in response to the COVID-19 pandemic, including the deployment of multiple video-conferencing systems and tools to ensure the impact of the transition was minimized for staff and students.

Director of Information Technology 08/2017 - 05/2019: Colton Joint Unified School District, Colton CAWorked collaboratively with all levels of staff and management to promote the effective use of technology.
Collaborated with leaders in education and industry groups to help foster technology innovation and growth.
Focused on improving cybersecurity to help prevent malware and ransomware attacks. Enabled the support of multiple client operating systems.

Assistant Director of Technology 09/2015 - 08/2017: Perris Union High School District, Perris CA

Worked with leaders in education and participated in local, regional and state groups to help foster technology innovation and growth. Researched new trends and solutions to ensure safe, reliable and equitable access to information to promote learning objectives in support of the District's mission and vision.

IT Supervisor 04/2014 - 09/2015: Perris Union High School District, Perris CA

Managed the operations of and supported a 1:1 program for over 10,000 students. Ensured infrastructure was maintained and continuously improved. Implemented a WAN with redundant fiber optic links, disaster recovery and campus wide WiFi. Provided training for IT staff to grow and develop professionally. Acted as a bridge between the demands of education and the technical complexities of IT.

Network Engineer 06/2013 - 04/2014: Perris Union High School District, Perris CA

Instrumental in the successful implementation of a district wide 1:1 program providing Chromebooks and WiFi to over 10,000 students. Improved access, reliability and security of network resources. Provided technical support, customer service guidance and resources to helpdesk and site based technicians.

IT Tech I 06/2006 - 06/2013: Perris Union High School District, Perris CA

Functional Systems Administrator 11/1997 - 7/2002: USAF, Hickam AFB, HI